johnlscott.com 2012-05-23

# John L. Scott Real Estate - John L. Scott - Privacy Policy

See also: [JLSconnect **™** Terms of Use](/jlsconnect-user-agreement.aspx)

John L. Scott Real Estate (BROKERAGE) promises to protect the personal information given to us by visitors to our website and information included on our electronic mail lists. Any information that you give to John L. Scott Real Estate will be held with the utmost care, and will not be used in any way to which you have not consented. A more detailed explanation follows. 

**COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION  
** Much of the general information on the John L. Scott Real Estate web site can be accessed without needing to register or log in – and we therefore collect no information about you whatsoever when you are accessing these generic areas of our web site. To search our database of properties for sale you may select one of three search methods. 

Anonymous: You may elect to remain completely anonymous when you search for properties on the John L. Scott Real Estate web site. If you select this option we do not collect any personal information from you. 

Property Tracker – no agent: Users who wish to access more detailed property information and extended searching features (such as the ability to save favorite listings, save searches and have new listings e-mailed to them automatically) may register to create a user account. To create a “Property Tracker” account visitors are asked to provide certain contact information. We do not sell, rent, loan, trade, or lease this personal information to anyone. NOTE: if your browser settings do not allow cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of some of the “Property Tracker” features. See below for more details about cookies. 

Property Tracker – with agent: Once you have created a “Property Tracker” account you may associate your account with a specific sales associate. When you select an associate to be “My Agent,” the sales associate you selected will be notified that you have done so, and will be provided with your contact information so that he/she may contact you for follow-up. The agent may also access details about your property search criteria, and lists of specific properties you have viewed through the John L. Scott Real Estate web site. In selecting an associate as “My Agent” you agree that your use of the John L. Scott Real Estate web site does not, in and of itself, create an agency relationship between you and the sales associate, or with any John L. Scott Real Estate brokerage company. However, further interactions between you and the sales associate (including contacts via e-mail, phone or in person) may result in establishing an agency relationship under the laws of your state, or the state where the agent is located. NOTE: if your browser settings do not allow cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of the “My Agent” features. See below for more details about cookies. 

Voluntary E-Mail Lists: Once you have registered to create a “Property Tracker” account, you will be invited to sign up to receive e-mail alerts about properties that match search criteria you establish. We configure our list server software to refuse to divulge the personal information on our list to anyone but us. The information is not, for example, available to other subscribers. Details on how to correct, change or remove subscription information from our email lists are provided on the “My Account” page after logging in to “Property Tracker.” 

Browser information collected on the website: As with many website operators, John L. Scott Real Estate analyzes our website logs to constantly improve the value of our website to our visitors. We maintain real-time reporting to us and our authorized agents of browser accesses to our site. This includes page views, unique views, unique visitors, repeat visitors, frequency of visits, and peak-volume traffic periods. In our use of this service, we do not gather, request, record, require, collect, or track any Internet users' personally identifiable information. 

Use of cookies: We use cookies on our website to provide each visitor with a personalized experience. Cookies are small data files that are downloaded onto your computer when you visit our site and that automatically identify your browser to our server whenever you interact with our site. We do link the cookies to your personally identifiable information on our servers, but no personal information is stored in the cookies themselves. We use cookies to track your use of our site, and to authenticate users of the “Property Tracker” and “My Agent” features. We do not share cookies with any other site. If you prefer not to allow us to collect cookie information, you can block cookies with your browser as described below. 

By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is sent, or to reject all cookies. For more information on how to modify your browser settings to block or filter cookies, see [http://www.cookiecentral.com/faq/](http://www.cookiecentral.com/faq). However, please note that if you reject some or all cookies, your experience at our site and on other sites throughout the World Wide Web may not be complete. Specifically, if you do not allow cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of the “Property Tracker” or “My Agent” features described above. 

Other uses of your personal information: In addition to using information about you for the specific purposes set out above, from time to time we may also use your personal information to send you news about our organization and new features available on the John L. Scott Real Estate web site. 

**DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION:**  
Resale or disclosure of information to third parties: John L. Scott Real Estate does not sell, rent, loan, trade, or lease personal information collected on our website or included on our e-mail lists to any third party. When John L. Scott Real Estate employs subcontractors that may have access to personal information, they are bound by a confidentiality agreement to ensure that they exercise the same level of care when handling your personal information as we do. 

**DATA SECURITY:**  
We take precautions to protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction. 

**DATA QUALITY AND ACCESS:**  
John L. Scott Real Estate provides you with the opportunity to know about the information that John L. Scott Real Estate holds about you, together with the ability to correct, amend or delete, as appropriate, any such information that is incomplete or inaccurate. Should you wish to exercise any of these options or should you have any questions or concerns about information that John L. Scott Real Estate has collected in relation to you, please feel free to contact us by sending a message to [contactus@johnlscott.com](mailto:contactus@johnlscott.com). Specific details on how to correct, change or remove subscription information from our e-mail lists are provided on the “My Account” page of “Property Tracker.” 

**ENFORCEMENT:**  
If for any reason you believe that John L. Scott Real Estate has not adhered to these privacy principles, please notify us by e-mail at [contactus@johnlscott.com](mailto:contactus@johnlscott.com), and we will endeavor to review and correct the problem promptly. Please use the words "Privacy Policy" in the Subject line. 

**EXTERNAL LINKS:**  
This website provides links to various websites that John L. Scott Real Estate does not control. When you click on one of these links, you will be transferred out of our website and connected to the website of the organization or company that you selected. Even if an affiliation exists between our website and a third party website, we exercise no control over linked sites. Each of these linked sites maintains its own independent privacy and data collection practices and procedures. If you visit a website that is linked to our site, you should consult that site's privacy policy before providing any personal information. 

**CHILDREN'S PRIVACY:**  
We comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulation establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children under 13. Our site is not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13. It is possible that due to fraud or deception by others, we may unknowingly receive information pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of this, once we have verified the information, we will promptly delete the information from our servers. If you want to notify us of our receipt of information in relation to children under 13, please do so by emailing us at [contactus@johnlscott.com](mailto:contactus@johnlscott.com). 

**INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION TRANSFERS**  
Any personally identifiable information that you provide to John L. Scott Real Estate will be collected directly on servers located in the United States and maintained on servers located in the United States. If you are located outside the United States, this means that any information you provide will be transferred abroad. While John L. Scott Real Estate is committed to providing your information with the highest level of privacy protection, we believe you should know that the general level of protection for personal information in the United States may not be the same as that provided in other countries, including those that belong to the European Economic Area. 

**TERMS AND MODIFICATIONS TO PRIVACY POLICY:  
** By using this website, you signify your agreement to the terms of our privacy policy. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not disclose any personal information through this site. John L. Scott Real Estate may modify this privacy policy at any time at its discretion and modifications are effective upon being posted on this site. You are responsible for reviewing this privacy policy periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes to it. 

**CONTACTING John L. Scott Real Estate ON PRIVACY:**  
If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy on the John L. Scott Real Estate website, please contact us at [contactus@johnlscott.com](mailto:contactus@johnlscott.com). 

This policy was last updated on November 1, 2004. 

See also: 

[JLSconnect **™** Terms of Use   
](/jlsconnect-user-agreement.aspx)
